Natsuko Shibuya, agent Jodie's friend is attacked by someone,
Teman Penyelidik Jodie, Natsuko Shibuya, diserang
rendered unconscious and is in critical condition.
tidak sadarkan diri dan dalam kondisi kritis.
Therefore, we rush over to see her.
Karena itu, kami bergegas menemuinya.
Three suspects are summoned.
Ketiga tersangka dipanggil.
Furthermore...
Dan...
It couldn't be helped.
Aku tidak punya pilihan.
She asked me to solve a stalker problem for her you see.
Dia memintaku untuk menyelidiki penguntitnya.
Bourbon?
Borbon?
After that, Bourbon and I through our deductions succeeded
Kemudian, Bourbon dan aku menentukan identitas pelakunya
in specifying the perpetrator. However...
dalam menentukan pelaku. Namun...
Excuse me!
Permisi!
The hospital just called.
Rumah sakit baru saja menelepon!
Ms. Shibuya took a turn for the worse
Kondisi Shibuya memburuk,
and she's in critical condition.
dan hidupnya dalam bahaya!
Natsuko?
Natsuko?
Natsuko!
Natsuko!
Oh, Jodie. You came all the way out here to see me.
Jodie, kau datang hanya untuk menemuiku.
Yes...
Ya.
But, it's amazing you knew that I regained consciousness.
Aku terkejut kau tahu aku sudah sadarkan diri.
Huh?
Apa?
As to what happened this time, I'm to blame too,
Ini terjadi karena sebagian adalah salahku,
so I feel quite uncomfortable.
jadi saya merasa sangat tidak nyaman.
I told them not to let the school know about it yet.
Jadi aku meminta mereka untuk tidak memberitahu sekolah.
This is bad.
Ini buruk!
Ms. Jodie!
Nn. Jodie!
Where's Agent Camel now?
Di mana Penyelidik Camel?
I think he's by the car?
Apa? Mungkin dengan mobilnya.
"Haido Central Hospital"
"Rumah Sakit Pusat Haido"
Rikumichi Kusuda?
Rikumichi Kusuda?
I don't know a guy like that.
Tidak kenal dia.
He's a guy who used to be hospitalized here,
Dia seorang pasien di rumah sakit ini.
stopped his car nearby and went missing.
Dia meninggalkan mobilnya di dekat sini dan menghilang.
I hear that there was a gun involved or something.
Kurasa ada senjata yang terlibat.
Haven't you heard anything about it from your buddies?
Apa kau dengar sesuatu?
Nope.
Siapa tahu?
Oh, I see!
Oh, benar.
I guess it's information that's not passed down
Informasinya tidak sampai
to a low-ranking agent like you.
ke penyelidik tahap rendah sepertimu.
Just what are you talking about?
Apa yang kau bicarakan?
We always share common information...
Kita selalu berbagi informasi...
Camel!
Camel!
Just what're you doing?
Apa yang sedang kau lakukan?
Stay with me, will you?
Tetaplah bersamaku, bisa, kan?
I hope you didn't tell him about Kusuda?
Aku harap kau tidak memberitahu dia tentang Kusuda.
Of course not.
Tentu tidak.
I wouldn't dare say that the guy shot himself to death in the car.
Aku takkan pernah memberitahunya bahwa dia menembak dirinya di dalam mobil.
My lips are sealed.
Bibirku tertutup rapat.
I see. Thank you.
Begitu. Terima kasih.
Well, it's an incident that occurred before I was dispatched to Japan,
Itu terjadi sebelum aku ditugaskan ke Jepang,
so I just heard about it from Mr. Akai.
jadi aku dengar tentang itu dari Akai.
Jodie?
Jodie?
Where are you?
Di mana kau?
Let's use the years we walked together as a springboard.
Didorong maju oleh tahun yang dihabiskan bersama.
And move forward full speed without slowing down.
Maju dengan kecepatan penuh tanpa memperlambat kecepatan.
What happened then?
Apa yang terjadi kemudian?
The dangerous conversation between two mysterious people.
Percakapan berbahaya antara dua orang misterius.
He sees through the one and only truth.
Dia melihat satu-satunya kebenaran.
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult.
Memiliki penampilan seorang anak kecil dengan kepintaran orang dewasa.
His name is Detective Conan!
Namanya adalah Detektif Conan.
"The Scarlet Interplay"
"Interaksi Scarlet"
"Haido Central Hospital" "The Day Before"
"Rumah Sakit Pusat Haido" "Hari Sebelumnya"
What?
Apa?
Jodie?
Jodie?
Camel!
Camel!
Jodie!
Jodie!
Is everything okay?
Apa semua baik-baik saja?
What do you mean?
Apa maksudmu?
That guy who is a member of the Organization, Amuro.
Amuro adalah seorang anggota dari Organisasi itu.
I saw his car drive out of this hospital.
Kami melihat mobilnya meninggalkan rumah sakit.
I hope you didn't leak any information out taken in by his glib talk?
Dia tidak membujukmu membocorkan rahasia, bukan?
No.
Tidak.
Rather, you said the same thing just a while ago too, didn't you?
Bukankah kau baru mengatakan itu?
What? A while ago?
Apa maksudmu?
Well, just a while ago, the exact same thing.
Kau mengatakan hal yang sama beberapa waktu lalu...
What're you talking about?
Apa yang kau bicarakan?
I just got back here from Natsuko's room just now.
Aku baru tiba di sini dari kamar Natsuko!
What?
Apa?
Then what about the Jodie I saw a while ago?
Lalu, ketika aku melihatmu tadi...
The skill to change the tone of voice and amazing disguising technique.
Sebuah suara dan penyamaran yang bisa membodohi teman.
A woman posses a combination of both.
Satu-satunya wanita dengan keduanya.
There's just one person.
Hanya ada satu orang.
It took you longer than I expected.
Kau terlambat.
I was worried that you wouldn't show up.
Aku pikir kau tidak akan datang.
I couldn't find a scarf that was similar to the kind she was wearing.
Aku kesulitan menemukan syal seperti miliknya.
I see.
Begitu.
And how did it go?
Jadi, bagaimana?
That guy called Kusuda.
Orangmu Kusuda...
Just as you assumed...
Kau benar.
He seems to have shot himself to death.
Dia sepertinya menembak dirinya sendiri.
In his own car.
Di dalam mobilnya sendiri.
So, it was just as I thought.
Begitu. Jadi itu yang terjadi...
What? Vermouth did?
Apa? Vermouth?
Are you saying that the Jodie I saw a while ago
Jodie yang kulihat tadi
was Vermouth in disguise?
adalah dia yang menyamar sebagai dirimu?
Yes.
Ya.
Bourbon asked you something, didn't he?
Bourbon pasti menanyakan sesuatu padamu.
Yeah, but I didn't answer him at all.
Ya, tapi aku tidak memberitahu apapun padanya.
He tried to provoke me by saying that
Dia berusaha menggoyahkanku dengan mengatakan
information isn't handed down to a low-ranking agent like me though.
infonya tidak sampai ke penyelidik rendah sepertiku.
He tries to provoke you mentally that way and pressure you.
Dia memprovokasimu agar kau lengah
Then, when your comrade, Jodie, comes around,
dan membiarkan sesuatu tergelincir
you feel comfortable and your tongue slips.
ketika Jodie muncul.
He uses that kind of psychology!
Dia memanipulasimu.
Wait up!
Tunggu.
You mean that Vermouth knew I was coming to this hospital
Apa itu artinya Vermouth tahu kita akan ke sini
and waiting for us here?
dan menunggu kita?
Yeah.
Ya.
We're just moving in accordance to how Bourbon and Vermouth want us to.
Semuanya berjalan sesuai rencana Bourbon dan Vermouth.
Just what do you mean?
Apa maksudmu?
It all started when you received the text mail from Ms. Shibuya, right?
Itu berawal dari surel yang kau terima dari Nn. Shibuya.
That's when Bourbon and Vermouth's strategy began!
Skema mereka dimulai di sana.
You mean that text mail she sent asking me to go drinking with her?
Undangannya untuk pergi minum?
Yes.
Ya.
Ms. Shibuya said that she didn't remember sending out such a mail, right?
Kau bilang Nn. Shibuya tak ingat mengirimkan surel itu, bukan?
Right.
Ya...
That is why I think that is the mail
Maka menurutku
that Bourbon had texted out from Ms. Shibuya's cell phone!
Bourbon mungkin mengirimnya dari ponsel milik Nn. Shibuya.
What?
Apa?
I think it's pretty difficult
Mencuri telepon
to steal the cell phone of an FBI like you.
dari seorang penyelidik FBI terdengar sulit.
But to secretly steal one of an ordinary elementary school teacher is easy.
Tapi mengambil ponsel guru sekolah dasar tanpa disadari mungkin mudah.
If Bourbon met Ms. Shibuya many times as a detective,
Jika dia telah bertemu dengan Nn. Shibuya beberapa kali sebagai detektif,
he would've had more than enough chances to do so.
dia akan punya banyak kesempatan.
But, why would he go that far to text out a mail like that?
Tapi kenapa dia mengirimkan pesan itu?
That's to make you call Ms. Shibuya
Agar kau menelepon Nn. Shibuya
using agent Camel's cell phone!
menggunakan ponsel Penyelidik Camel.
What?
Apa?
If it's to go drinking, the time would be night.
Jika kau akan pergi minum, kau akan bertemu pada malam hari.
He knew that at around that time
Dia tahu pada waktu itu
your cell phone would be out of battery.
ponselmu sudah mati
He was watching us.
Mereka memperhatikan kita.
But why my cell phone?
Tapi kenapa ponselku?
Any FBI agent would've been fine.
Penyelidik FBI manapun bisa.
So long as some sort of accident happened to Ms. Shibuya that night,
Jika sesuatu terjadi pada Nn. Shibuya malam itu,
the agent whose call history was left on her cell phone,
penyelidik yang nomornya ada pada sejarah panggilannya
would be called to come along with you.
dan Jodie akan dipanggil ke tempat kejadian.
I see.
Begitu.
So in other words
Maka dari awal,
his target was the FBI agent that came along with me to begin with.
mereka bermaksud mendapatkan informasi dari agen yang menemaniku.
But Natsuko was pushed off the stairs of the park by Mr. Kandachi
Tapi Natsuko terluka setelah Pak Kandachi mendorongnya
and seriously injured,
dari tangga taman.
what if that never occurred?
Bagaimana jika itu tidak terjadi?
Maybe he was planning to run her over and seriously injure her.
Mungkin mereka bermaksud untuk menabraknya dengan mobil.
After all, Bourbon said he was riding a car.
Bourbon bilang dia mengendarai mobilnya.
No matter what method he used,
Bagaimanapun,
I think he was planning to get her into an accident outside.
mereka bermaksud untuk melukainya di luar ruangan.
Outside?
Di luar ruangan?
Right.
Ya.
In order to confirm the clothes that you were wearing, Jodie.
Jadi mereka tahu bagaimana kau berpakaian.
My clothes?
Bagaimana aku berpakaian?
Your face can be disguised with the pictures of you that had been taken
Mereka bisa menyiapkan topeng dari foto-foto,
but it doesn't work out with the clothes that you're wearing today.
tapi itu tidak berlaku untuk pakaian yang kau kenakan hari ini.
Rather than have you stay in the car or inside a room,
Lebih mudah untuk melihat dan mengambil foto dirimu
it would be easier to get a full view of you
jika kau di luar
or take sneak photos of you outside.
daripada di dalam gedung atau mobil.
And once the disguise is ready,
Begitu penyamarannya siap,
he lures you, Jodie, over to the hospital by saying that
mereka menelepon untuk mengatakan kondisi Nn. Shibuya memburuk
Ms. Shibuya's condition had worsened or something.
dan membawamu ke rumah sakit.
He distracted agent Camel to get you away from him.
Mereka menarik perhatian Camel untuk memisahkan dia darimu.
Which means that Vermouth, who disguised herself as me,
Jadi Vermouth, menyamar sebagai aku,
successfully got you to give out information?
bisa mendapat informasi darimu.
I'm sorry.
Maaf...
But Conan, from about when did you realize all this?
Tapi Conan, kapan kau pertama menyadarinya?
When we got the call from the hospital.
Ketika rumah sakit menelepon.
Because if it's about the patient, who's involved in a case,
Seorang pasien yang terlibat dalam kasus
the police would be contacted,
mungkin punya informasi untuk polisi.
but as to anything other than that, only the family is contacted.
Tapi mereka hanya boleh memberitahu keluarga tentang kondisi pasien.
Conan, then why didn't you tell me about it?
Kenapa kau tidak memberitahuku?
I wasn't sure yet.
Aku belum yakin.
There's a possibility that she could've been disguised as Ms. Shibuya too.
Mungkin dia menyamar sebagai Nn. Shibuya.
Really?
Benarkah?
But what on earth was Bourbon after?
Tapi bagaimana dengan Bourbon?
And? What information did you leak?
Apa yang kau katakan padanya?
Oh, yes.
Ya...
About their spy who was hospitalized at this hospital, Rikumichi Kusuda.
Tentang Rikumichi Kusuda, mata-mata mereka yang menyusup ke rumah sakit.
The one who shot himself in his own car!
Bahwa dia menembak dirinya di dalam mobilnya.
Is that all?
Itu saja?
Yes.
Ya.
Since Conan had warned me about it in the car on our way here,
Dalam perjalanan ke sini, Conan menarik perhatianku pada hal itu,
my tongue slipped.
jadi itu ada di pikiranku.
But what kind of merit is it them getting such information out of you?
Tapi bagaimana informasi itu membantu mereka?
Well...
Yah...
If Kusuda, who they thought was nabbed by the FBI, is dead,
Jika orang yang mereka pikir ditangkap oleh FBI sudah tewas,
there's no worry of him leaking anything out, I guess?
mereka tidak harus cemas tentang dia akan membuka suara.
I wonder if there's some other meaning to this?
Atau itu bisa berarti hal lain?
How about it, Conan?
Benar, Conan?
Conan?
Conan?
Hey, Conan.
Hei, Conan?
What's the matter?
Ada apa?
Conan?
Conan?
What's this Rikumichi Kusuda about?
Jadi siapa Rikumichi Kusuda?
I hear he was a member of the Organization.
Dia adalah anggota Organisasi.
What's the big deal about a man, who wasn't even given a code name,
Tapi apa pentingnya jika seorang pria tanpa kode nama
shooting himself to death?
menembak dirinya?
If you were to commit suicide using a gun,
Jika kau ingin bunuh diri dengan pistol,
what would you do?
apa yang akan kau lakukan?
Well...
Yah...
I would point the muzzle of the gun to the temple.
Aku akan letakkan moncong di pelipisku.
That's right.
Ya.
And the mark of the bullet would clearly remain in the skull
Meninggalkan lubang peluru yang jelas di tengkorakmu
even if the corpse were to be burned.
meskipun tubuhmu hangus.
What?
Apa?
There was such an incident.
Ada kejadian seperti itu.
About the time the whereabouts of Kusuda became unknown.
Soal waktu keberadaan Kusuda menjadi tidak diketahui.
Just about the same time,
Di saat yang sama,
there was a man who was shot in the head and burned.
ada pria lain yang kepalanya ditembak dan dibakar.
That's...
Maksudmu bukan...
Right.
Ya.
FBI agent,
Penyelidik FBI,
Shuichi Akai.
Shuichi Akai.
Don't tell me...
Mustahil!
That he's alive?
Maksudmu dia masih hidup?
Yes. If my deduction is correct.
Ya, jika aku benar.
Too bad, but your deduction's way off.
Maaf, tapi kau salah.
Because his death was confirmed.
Kematiannya sudah dikonfirmasi.
Furthermore, the people who confirmed it are the Japanese police
Dikonfirmasi oleh kepolisian Jepang
and the people who made them confirm that was the FBI.
atas permintaan FBI.
I mentioned before, didn't I?
Bukankah aku sudah memberitahumu?
That the fingerprints of Akai's corpse that Kir shot the head of
Sidik jari dari jasad Akai yang Kir tembak di kepala
at Raiha Pass and burned together with his car,
di Raiha Pass dan dibakar beserta mobilnya,
and the fingerprints of Akai
sesuai sidik jari Akai
found on that detective boy's cell phone matched.
yang tertinggal di ponsel bocah detektif itu.
I see.
Begitu.
But, how were you able to get the fingerprints from a corpse?
Tapi bagaimana kau mendapatkan sidik jari dari jasad yang terbakar?
That's because he was burned with one hand inside the pocket
Karena dia terbakar dengan tangannya
of his fireproof slacks.
di dalam saku jaket anti apinya.
That's the kind of guy he is...
Pria seperti itulah dia...
Even back when he shot me with his shotgun,
Ketika dia menembakku dengan shotgun,
he had one hand in his pocket too.
satu tangannya di dalam sakunya.
Using a shotgun with one hand?
Menembak shotgun dengan satu tangan?
Just like him to do so.
Terdengar seperti dia.
But it's also thinkable that one hand was put in the pocket
Tapi mungkin tangannya ada di dalam saku
so that fingerprints could be taken later.
agar kau menemukan sidik jarinya kemudian.
If you're that suspicious,
Jika kau sangat meragukanku,
would you like to see the image of when Akai was shot?
kau mau lihat video ketika Akai ditembak?
You mean the video that Kir took with the hidden camera
Maksudmu film yang diambil oleh kamera tersembunyi
he was wearing around his neck back then.
di leher Kir?
Right.
Ya.
The video in which that guy was definitely killed
Kau bisa melihat dengan jelas
was clearly taken on that camera.
dia menghembuskan nafas terakhirnya.
What's the matter, Kir?
Ada apa, Kir?
Hurry and finish him off.
Habisi dia.
But since I already shot through his lung,
Tapi aku menembaknya di paru-paru.
he'll be dead in about 30 minutes even if I leave him as is.
Meskipun aku meninggalkan dia, dia hanya dapat bertahan sekitar 30 menit.
His head.
Kepalanya.
Blast a bullet into his head
Tembak dia di kepala.
That'll kill him off for sure.
Maka kita akan tahu pasti bahwa hidupnya sudah berakhir.
Roger.
Baik.
And before he was shot in the head, he mumbled...
Sebelum dia menembaknya di kepala, dia bilang...
I didn't think you'd go this far.
Untuk berpikir kau bertindak sejauh ini.
I'm surprised too.
Aku juga terkejut.
I'd like to comment from the standpoint of an actress,
Bicara sebagai sesama aktor,
it was no preset dialogue.
dia tidak berencana untuk mengatakan itu.
Those were words that came from the bottom of the heart.
Itu hal yang sungguh dia rasakan.
It was no act.
Itu bukan sebuah penampilan.
I'm disappointed though,
Tapi aku kecewa kau menyeretku ke dalam masalah ini.
that I had to play along with such a farce.
Untuk berpikir kau bertindak sejauh ini...
"I didn't think you'd go this far..."
"Untuk berpikir kau bertindak sejauh ini..."
"I didn't think you'd go this far."
"Untuk berpikir kau bertindak sejauh ini."
I didn't think you'd go this far.
Untuk berpikir kau bertindak sejauh ini.
I see, that's the story.
Begitu.
Well, I'll prove whether my deduction is correct or not.
Aku akan buktikan padamu entah aku benar atau tidak.
After cornering him into a circumstance
Setelah menyudutkannya
where he can't say a word or find his way out of.
dimana dia tak bisa bicara atau mencari jalan keluar.
So I guess you know the whereabouts of that ghost, then.
Jadi kau tahu ke mana untuk menemukan hantunya?
No, not yet.
Tidak, belum.
As long as I know the trick,
Tapi begitu aku dapat petunjuk,
for me to check up on it is more than easy.
akan butuh kurang dari sehari bagiku
I can do it in less than a day.
untuk menyelidikinya.
Is Conan going to be absent today?
Apa Conan tetap di rumah hari ini?
Yes, it seems he caught a cold and is in bed.
Ya. Dia di kasur terkena flu.
What? And today's school lunch is curry rice!
Apa? Tapi kita akan makan kari untuk makan siang hari ini!
Is that what you're worried about?
Kau mencemaskan itu?
Well, it's curry, you know, curry!
Tapi itu kari!
It even comes with pudding!
Bahkan ada pudingnya!
Well, since he was secretly doing things with Dr. Agasa yesterday,
Nah, karena dia diam-diam melakukan sesuatu dengan Dr. Agasa kemarin,
I'm not sure if he really has a cold or not.
Aku tidak yakin dia benar-benar terkena flu.
"Mouri Detective Agency"
"Kantor Detektif Mouri"
Conan!
Conan!
What time was the Macademy Awards?
Kapan Penghargaan Macademy dimulai?
What?
Tunggu, apa?
Dad, isn't Conan back from school yet?
Ayah, Conan masih belum pulang dari sekolah?
That brat called to say that he's staying over at Dr. Agasa's place
Dia menelepon untuk mengatakan dia menginap di rumah Dokter Agasa
so he wouldn't be eating dinner here.
jadi dia tidak perlu makan malam.
No!
Tidak!
I was looking forward to watching the Macademy Awards with him.
Aku menantikan untuk melihat Penghargaan Macademy bersama dengannya.
What's so good about a foreign movie award program?
Siapa yang peduli tentang upacara penghargaan film asing?
Well, Shinichi's father has been nominated for the best script award.
Tapi ayah Shinichi dinominasikan untuk Skrip Original Terbaik!
That's something to look forward to, isn't it?
Bukankah itu menyenangkan?
Okay, I can see why you would be,
Mungkin untukmu,
but why would that brat also be looking forward to it?
tapi kenapa anak itu peduli?
I guess so.
Kurasa kau benar.
Come on. Never mind that already. Hurry and make dinner.
Bagaimanapun, siapkan makan malam di meja!
I'm starving.
Aku lapar!
Then, first for the best supporting actor award.
Mari mulai dengan Aktor Pendukung Terbaik.
This year's presenter is last year's award winner,
Membawakan penghargaan tahun ini adalah pemenang tahun lalu,
Mr. Johnny Bip!
Johnny Bip.
"Kudo"
"Kudo"
Yes.
Ya?
Delivery.
Pengantaran.
Good evening.
Selamat sore.
How do you do?
Senang bertemu denganmu.
I'm Tohru Amuro.
Aku Tohru Amuro.
I see...
Begitu...
But, this is not our first meeting, is it?
Tapi ini bukan kali pertama kita bertemu, bukan?
I'd like to talk to you a bit.
Aku ingin bicara.
Would it be okay for me to go inside?
Boleh aku masuk?
Yes, if it's just you.
Tentu, tapi hanya kau.
I'm sorry,
Maafkan aku,
but the others that are waiting outside are not invited in.
tapi bisakah teman-temanmu menunggu di luar?
Because I don't think I have enough teacups to serve them tea with.
Aku rasa aku tidak memiliki cukup banyak cangkir teh.
Please don't worry about them.
Jangan cemaskan mereka.
They love to wait outside.
Mereka suka menunggu di luar.
But depending on how you answer me.
Tapi tergantung pada jawabanmu,
We may all have to barge in here.
kami mungkin berakhir masuk semua.
Raiha Pass?
Raiha Pass?
You mean we're going to the place
Kita akan pergi ke tempat
where Mr. Akai was killed by them from now?
di mana mereka membunuh Akai?
Yes.
Ya.
I feel as if I can get a hold of something if we go.
Kurasa kita akan menemukan sesuatu di sana.
Right.
Benar.
The time I was informed that Kusuda shot himself...
Ekspresi yang dia buat ketika dia mengetahui mereka tahu
That facial expression.
Kusuda menembak dirinya sendiri.
And the total confusion during the flower viewing season.
Dan ketika dia kehilangan kendalinya selama insiden melihat bunga itu.
There's definitely something.
Pasti ada sesuatu di sana.
There's something!
Pasti.
"Raiha Pass"
"Raiha Pass"
"Next Episode" -Do you like mysteries?
"Episode Selanjutnya" -Apa kau suka misteri?
Then, shall we start there?
Maka, mari kita mulai di sana.
But the skinny man who came after the man in question who was killed,
Tapi pria tewas itu menyentuh ponsel itu
was also holding the same cell phone, wasn't he?
setelah pria kurus itu, bukan?
But Mr. Akai touched that cell phone
Tapi Akai menyentuh ponsel itu
only before he let them recapture Rena Mizunashi, right?
sebelum dia mengijinkan mereka untuk menangkap kembali Rena Mizunashi.
Next Conan, "The Scarlet Return"
Selanjutnya dalam Conan, "Kembalinya Scarlet"